A Guide to the Sara Teasdale Collection
University of Virginia Library
- LETTERS
  - Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, to Vine Colby McCasland, Pasadena, California, 1932 Mar 4; ALS, 10 p. on 10 l. (Box Box 9)
    thanking her profusely for the gift of a butterfly, mentioning Jay Van Everen's praise of it, referring to her essay on Christina Rossetti, discussing Virginia Woolf, comparing the views of the Empire State Building and the Eiffel Tower, and saying she would be glad to meet Mary Ware Dennett
  - Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, to Vine Colby McCasland, Pasadena, California, 1932 Apr 15; A & TLS, 5 p. on 3 l. (Box Box 9)
    discussing the lingering effects of the Depression on New York, and her frail physical condition and wanting to leave New York; and, mentioning Mrs. Vachel Lindsay, her own biography of Christina Rossetti, and friends
  - Williamina Parrish, Paris, France, to Vine Colby McCasland, Pasadena, California, 1932 June 10; APCS (Box Box 9)
  - Sara Teasdale Filsinger, New York, New York, to Vine Colby McCasland, Pasadena, California, 1932 June 23; ALS, 7 p. on 4 l. (Box Box 9)
    discussing her decreased income, work on her essay about Christina Rossetti, and personal news
  - Sara Teasdale Filsinger, London, England, to Vine Colby McCasland, Pasadena, California, 1932 Aug 21; APCS (Box Box 9)
    mentioning meeting Christina Rossetti's two nieces
  - Williamina Parrish, Seville, Spain, to Vine Colby McCasland, 1932 Oct 25; ALS, 9 p. on 3 l. (Box Box 9)
    discussing life in Spain; and giving a personal discourse on the relationships of George Bernard Shaw and Ellen Terry and Henry Irving, and comparing Terry to Eleonora Duse as an actress and lover
  - Williamina Parrish, Tetuan, Spanish Morocco, to Vine Colby McCasland, Pasadena, California, with ANS from Grace Parrish, 1932 Oct 31; APCS (Box Box 9)
  - Williamina Parrish to Vine Colby McCasland, 1932 Oct; A & TL, 3 p. on 2 l., w/enclosures (Box Box 9)
  - Susan Meriwether Boogher Bryan, Havre De Grace, Maryland, to Vine Colby McCasland, 1933 Jan 14; ALS, 12 p. on 6 l. (Box Box 9)
    mentioning the latter's "Crumbs," Sarah Bernhardt and Eleonora Duse, William Marion Reedy and Tyrell Williams, and Virginia Woolf
  - Williamina Parrish to Vine Colby McCasland, 1933 Mar 22; ALS, 6 p. on 2 l., with enclosures (Box Box 9)
    expressing her feelings about the gift of the beautiful butterfly and the importance of childhood memories
  - Williamina Parrish to Vine Colby McCasland, 1933 Mar 28; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 9)
    concerning some pictures of Sara Teasdale
  - Williamina Parrish to Vine Colby McCasland, 1933 Apr 4; ALS, 6 p. on 2 l. (Box Box 9)
    discussing Sara Teasdale's suicide
  - Mary Ware Dennett to Vine Colby McCasland, 1933 Oct 10; ALS, 7 p. on 7 l. (Box Box 9)
    mentioning Williamina Parrish, Martha Prentice Merwin, and Upton Sinclair
  - Williamina Parrish to Vine Colby McCasland, 1933 Nov 21; TL (Box Box 9)
    enclosing horoscope and related enclosures
  - Williamina Parrish to Vine Colby McCasland, 1933 Nov 27; TLS, 2 p. on 2 l. (Box Box 9)
    discussing Morgan McCormick and Isabel (Parrish) McCormick
  - Williamina Parrish to Vine Colby McCasland, [1933 Nov] Sunday; TLS, 1 p., with related enclosures (Box Box 9)
    sending additional horoscope material
  - Williamina Parrish to Vine Colby McCasland, 1934 Jan 8; TLS, 3 p. on 3 l. (Box Box 9)
    remembering Sara Teasdale's death and mentioning old friends
  - Mamie Teasdale Whelass, New York, New York, to Vine Colby McCasland, 1934 Jan 12; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 9)
    sending a photograph of Sara Teasdale; and, discussing Sara's wishes after her death: the Christina Rossetti book and other works remaining unpublished and keeping her life private
  - Susan Meriwether Boogher Bryan to Vine Colby McCasland, 1934 May 4; TLS, 3 p. on 3 l. (Box Box 9)
    writing news of Tyrell Williams and Nell Niedringhaus Williams and biographical information
  - Williamina Parrish, Firenze, Ferrovia, Italy, to Vine Colby McCasland, Pasadena, California, 1934 Aug 28; APCS (Box Box 9)
  - Mary D. Harris, Lincoln, Nebraska, to "My Gallant Potters, " St. Louis, Missouri, n.y. June 24; ALS, 6 p. on 2 l. (Box Box 9)
    writing family news and mentioning Celia [E. Harris]
  - Celia E. Harris, Lincoln, Nebraska, to Williamina Parrish, St. Louis, Missouri, n.y. Aug 10; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 9)
    mentioning Vine Colby, Petronelle Sombart, Edna "Ned" Wahlert, and Edith Wyatt
  - Sara Teasdale to Vine Colby, n.y. [Dec]; APCS (Box Box 9)
  - Sara Teasdale to Vine Colby, n.y. [Dec]; ANS (Box Box 9)
  - Celia E. Harris, Lincoln, Nebraska, to Williamina Parrish, St. Louis, Missouri, n.d. Monday; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 9)
    mentioning Caroline Risque, Vine Colby, and briefly describing her life in Lincoln
  - [Mary D. Harris], Mercy Hospital, to "My dear Potters, ", n.d. Tuesday; AL, 6 p. on 2 l. (Box Box 9)
    describing the pleasure that the
    Potter's Wheels
    brings her and others, mentioning Celia E. Harris' convalescence, with ANS from Celia, mentioning her own and Sara Teasdale's illnesses
  - Vine Colby to [Williamina Parrish], n.d.; ANS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 9)
  - Vine Colby to Williamina Parrish, n.d.; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 9)
    ordering photographs
  - Mary D. Harris to [the Potters], n.d.; ALS (fragment), 3 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 9)
    acknowledging the photographs of Celia E. Harris
  - Williamina Parrish(and Grace Parrish), Paris, France, to Vine Colby, APCS (Box Box 9)
  - "Guglielmina" [Williamina Parrish] ti "Signorina Vino" [Vine Colby], n.d.; ANS (Box Box 9)
  - Sara Teasdale, Oxford, England, to Vine Colby, APCS (Box Box 9)
  - Sara Teasdale to Vine Colby, n.d.; APCS (Box Box 9)
    from an "enchanting old place"
- PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Photograph of Sara Teasdale and her mother, Mary Elizabeth Willard Teasdale, 1888; Sepia (Box Box 9)
  - Photographs of Vine Colby posing nude on the beach at Charlevoix, Michigan, taken by Williamina Parrish, ca. 1905; 35 items (Box Box 9)
  - Photographs of Mary Elizabeth Willard Teasdale, 1907, n.d.; 2 items (Box Box 9)
  - Photographs of Marion Cummings Stanley and Sara Teasdale, 1908-1909; 8 items (Box Box 9)
  - Photograph of the Teasdale family home, signed on back "For mamma from Sara", 1910 June; 1 item (Box Box 9)
  - Photograph of John Warren Teasdale, n.d.; 1 item (Box Box 9)
- MISCELLANEOUS
  - Greek Ethics Club re the fourth session topic, "Little Dorrit", 1904 Dec 9; PC (Box Box 9)
  - State Historical Society of Missouri circulars sent to Sara Teasdale, 1908 Sep 4; Circulars (Box Box 9)
  - Program for "Whitsuntide, Ye Comet's Tail," a play by Williamina Parrish and Vine Colby, 1908 Sep 23; Printed (Box Box 9)
  - "The Broader Field of Art," The Modern View, by F. E. A. Curley, re Potters work in exhibit at St. Louis Museum of Fine Arts, 1908 Sep; Printed (Box Box 9)
  - Invitation to the Dinner of the Poetry Society of America and the National Arts Club, 1910 Dec 14; Printed (Box Box 9)
  - Form letter inviting recipient to become an active member of the Poetry Society of America, 1910 Dec 23; Printed (Box Box 9)
  - The Poetry Society of America announcement of the next meeting, signed by Jessie Belle Rittenhouse, 1911 Jan 21; Printed (Box Box 9)
  - The Poetry Society of America announcement of the next meeting, 1911 Dec; Printed (Box Box 9)
  - Index of Seats for the Dinner of the Poetry Society of America and the National Arts Club, with AN by Sara Teasdale about the people she met, 1912 Jan 23; Printed (Box Box 9)
  - Acceptance of poems by Sara Teasdale from J. B. Lippincott Company, with AN listing "To One Away" and "Two Friends", 1912 June 4; Printed (Box Box 9)
  - Request for permission to publish a song, "Pierrot," with words by Sara Teasdale from G. Schirmer, 1912 Aug 29; Printed (Box Box 9)
  - Acceptances of poems by Sara Teasdale from The Smart Set, with type listing "Sea Longing" and "Broadway", 1912 Dec 26; Printed (Box Box 9)
  - Payment for serial rights for poems by Sara Teasdale from Charles Scribner's Sons, with type listing "Sappho" and "The River", 1913 Jan 27; Printed (Box Box 9)
  - Index of Seats for the Annual Dinner of the Poetry Society of America, with ANS from Louis Untermeyer, 1913 Jan 28; Printed (Box Box 9)
  - The Poetry Society of America Minutes, 1913 Dec 22; Printed (Box Box 9)
  - Index of Seats for the Annual Dinner of the Poetry Society of America, 1914 Jan 28; Printed (Box Box 9)
  - Calling card of "Mrs. Ernst B. Filsinger" with announcement of the reading of her [ Sara Teasdale Filsinger] poems by Mr. Filsinger (in her hand), post 1914; AN (Box Box 9)
  - Acceptance of poem by Sara Teasdale from The Bellman with type listing "Spring in War-Time", 1915 Apr 6; Printed (Box Box 9)
  - Regret of poem by Sara Teasdale from The Frank A. Munsey Company, w/ANS listing "Chance" as being accepted, 1915 Apr 12; Printed (Box Box 9)
  - Announcements of publication of Rivers to the Sea by Sara Teasdale, 1915 Oct; Printed (Box Box 9)
  - Announcement of publication of Anthology of Magazine Verse by William Stanley Braithwaite, 1915; Printed (Box Box 9)
  - Index of Seats for the Annual Dinner of the Poetry Society of America, 1916 Jan 25; Printed (Box Box 9)
  - Acceptance of poem by Sara Teasdale from The Bellman, with type listing "After Death", 1916 Jan 28; Printed (Box Box 9)
  - Publication material on Rivers to the Sea by Sara Teasdale, compiled by Philip Roeder Book and Stationery Company, 1916 Apr 15; Printed (Box Box 9)
  - "The Sentimentalist," The Smart Set, by Sara Teasdale, 1916 Apr; Printed 4 p. (Box Box 9)
  - Acceptance of poem by Sara Teasdale from The Bellman with type listing "Remembered Beauty", 1916 May 19; Printed (Box Box 9)
  - The Poetry Society of America Bulletin, 1916 May; Printed, 8 p. (Box Box 9)
  - The Poetry Society of America Bulletin, 1917 May; Printed, 8 p. (Box Box 9)
  - Acceptance of poem by Sara Teasdale from The Bellman with type listing "In a Burying Ground", 1917 July 23; Printed (Box Box 10)
  - The Bang, a weekly publication by editor Alexander Harvey, 1917 Nov 5; Printed 8 p. (Box Box 10)
  - Index of Seats for the Annual Dinner of the Poetry Society of America, 1918 Jan 31; Printed (Box Box 10)
  - "The Story of an American Publishing House," a pamphlet re The MacMillan Company, 1918; Printed (Box Box 10)
  - Index of Seats for the Annual Dinner of the Poetry Society of America, 1919 Jan 30; Printed (Box Box 10)
  - Invitation to a tea with the Potters, written and drawn in water color, n.y. Aug 20; ANS (Box Box 10)
- BOUND VOLUMES
  - "The Potter's Wheel," critique of Volume II, Number II, December, by Williamina Parrish, Sara Teasdale, and Edna Wahlert, 1906; AMsS (Box Box 10)
  - Scrapbook (Book I) kept by Sara Teasdale, which includes poems, reviews, letters, and other memorabilia about her and her work, 1907-1910; Bound Volume (Box Box 10)
  - "Ye Comet's Tail," a tragedy in three acts by Williamina Parrish and Vine Colby, including typescript and photographs, made into a book by W. P. for V. C. in 1933, with fragment ANS from Sara Teasdale in front cover, 1908; Bound Voume (Box Box 10)
  - Autograph Book owned by Sara Teasdale Filsinger, with 35 pages of poetry by Margaret Conklin on verso, 1931 Oct 17; Bound Volume (Box Box 10)
  - "Crumbs" by Vine Colby McCasland, a booklet of random thoughts presented to Mary Ware Dennett, 1932 May; TMs (Box Box 10)
  - "Plums (alias Prunes)" Williamina Parrish, a booklet of random thoughts presented to Vine Colby McCasland, 1933; TMs (Box Box 10)
  - "The Potters by W. and G. Parrish/ for Aunt Rose", Photograph Album (Box Box 10)
  - "The Potters. Portraits by W. and G. Parrish, Saint Louis", Photograph Album (Box Box 10)
- MEMORABILIA
  - Baby ring given to Inez Dutro George's baby, Barbara George, by Sara Teasdale, 1908; 1 item
  - Rosary of olive stones brought by Sara Teasdale from the Holy Lands and given to Williamina Parrish, 1 item
- OVERSIZE
  - "The Potter's Wheel," Volume I, Number VI, including an ALS, March 16, 1905, from Sara Teasdale, Cairo, Egypt, to "My dear Fellow Potters", 1905 Apr; Bound Volume (Box Slipcase I)
  - "The Potter's Wheel," Volume I, Number XI, including "Heart and Soul," "The Pet Bird," and "Sonnet" by Sara Teasdale, 1905 Sep; Bound Volume (Box Slipcase I)
  - "The Potter's Wheel," Volume II, Number II, including "Triolets," "To Joy A Sonnet," and "Dedication" by Sara Teasdale, 1905 Dec; Bound Volume (Box Slipcase II)
  - "The Potter's Wheel," Volume II, Number V, including "Sonnets to Pictures of Eleonora Duse" and "A Fable" by Sara Teasdale, 1906 Mar; Bound Volume (Box Slipcase II)
  - "The Potter's Wheel," Volume X, Number II, including "To Sappho" and "Unto the Third and Fourth Generation" by Sara Teasdale, 1906 Aug; Bound Volume (Box Slipcase II)
  - "The Potters' Wheel," including "The Lonely Road" and "To W. P. with a Book of Celtic Verse" by Sara Teasdale, 1907 Feb; Bound Volume (Box Slipcase II)
  - "The Potters' Log," kept by Vine Colby, Scribe for the group, from October 13, 1905 to October 14, 1906. The Log contains the records entered by Vine and pencil sketches by Caroline Risque. Also included is an "Index to the Tricks, Manners and Opinions of the Potters. ", 1905-1906; Bound Volume (Box Slipcase II)
  - "The Potters' Log," kept by Vine Colby, Scribe for the group, from January 1 to ca. July, 1907. Included with the records are photographs of the Potters, invitations and place-cards, clippings, programs, and other memorabilia. There are also letters from Susan Creighton Williams(January 3, 1907 and n.d.), Bound Volume (Box Slipcase II)
  - Scrapbook (Book II) kept by Sara Teasdale, which includes poems, reviews, letters, and other memorabilia about her and her work, 1910-1915; Bound Volume (Box Loose Volume)
  - Scrapbook (Book III) kept by Sara Teasdale, which includes poems, reviews, letters, and other memorabilia about her and her work, 1915-1917; Bound Volume (Box Loose Volume)
  - Scrapbook (Book IV) kept by Sara Teasdale, which includes poems, reviews, letters, and other memorabilia about her and her work, 1917-1919; Bound Volume (Box Loose Volume)